We're uh
we're excited about today. Um you know,
not just with the players that we added,
the three guys that we added, but um
also how we were able to add to our um
our resource base uh in 27 um and then
how we're positioned for for tomorrow
afternoon. Um you know, with several
other day three picks. So, uh obviously
a lot of action, a lot of movement um
you know, throughout the evening
tonight, but we're pleased with where we
ended up. And so with that, I'll open up
with questions.
>> And I'm sure you didn't come into
thinking you'd make this many trades,
but when you get a sense that it could
be just that kind of night for you.
>> It's usually just based on the action
that you get or how the board falls. Um,
I'll be honest, Dan, like we're pretty
like we try to stay pretty nimble and
flexible just because you never know,
you know, when the next opportunity is
going to come up. I think that's
actually one of the benefits of having
volume and quality with your picks
because there are more opportunities to
maneuver up and down the board. That
being said, were you surprised with some
of the guys that fell in your lap like
Denzel Mos to begin with? They were
first round projections.
>> I was probably most surprised with Eman.
Um, you know, we figured that Denzel
could go anywhere from late one to to
early two just to be truthful. Um, but
Eman, he wasn't someone that we
anticipated being, you know, being there
as late as he was. So, um, when he got
within striking distance, you know, we
felt the move was appropriate. You know,
to be truthful, he was in play for us at
39.
um look at what you did with your wide
receiver room. Can you sort of talk
about what you have globally from your
pass catching core right now and how
this might impact like a Jerry Judy or
or anybody like that?
>> Zero impact on Jerry. He's our bellcow.
Um we feel like we have a nice uh I
think with receiver rooms you can have,
you know, maybe a ball dominant player
or you can essentially build a
basketball team, you know, with
different skill sets. Um you know, we
prefer the the second approach. Now,
don't get me wrong, I'll take Calvin
Johnson if he's if he's out there, but
um we feel like we have a nice, you
know, well-rounded room with speed,
rack, um contested catch ability,
separation. Um so, we're we're really
pleased with um you know, the youth and
talent in that group.
>> On that on that trade,
>> uh for Emanuel, do you get a sense that
another team is going to take or when do
you know when to pull the trigger on
that? So there they're there they're
there probably two separate situations,
Jeff. Um one is when you and one is when
you do have maybe an inkling that you
know you're going into a a stretch where
um you and a player or a group of
players you know will be target for
several teams and you're trying to get
ahead of it. Another may just be um and
I would put like the Emanuel trade and
then what we did for J in 2021 in this
bucket where you have a player that you
just didn't expect to be in a certain
range of the draft and there's a certain
level of like okay you don't necessarily
have a a team identified that's going to
take that player off the board but you
look at your resources and say hey this
is a price that I'm I'm willing to pay
for this skill set for this guy um
relative to what you think you're
getting.
I'll go here and then I'll go Ashley. Y
>> you talked last week before the draft
just about that positionless defense. Um
where does where does a player like
Emanuel Warren sort of fit into to that
that idea as you think about what you
got in him as a player?
>> Yeah. Well, I Emanuel is incredibly
versatile and and you know, we're um
realistic that you're not going to put
everything on his plate his rookie year.
Um, but I think you really started
seeing this with the safety positions,
certainly with what Baltimore did with
Kyle Hamilton a couple years ago. Um,
you look across the league and you see
uh just the increase of three safety
packages. You look at what um you know,
Emani, Nick Mory did for for Seattle
this past year and it just gives you a
lot of flexibility where you have
safeties that can play deep, they can
play in the box, they can live in the
linebacker world, they can live in the
the the nickel world and um they just
give a lot of flexibility for a creative
coordinator.
>> Remember last year after you guys
drafted Carson, you talked about the
importance of taking an off ball
linebacker that high because you hadn't
made a major investment there since like
four years prior. Was was there any
similar thinking with Emanuel like you
hadn't taken a safety that high since
Grant like six years ago.
>> No, it it really wasn't because you know
Grant and Ronnie we obviously like those
guys a lot. Um you know Grant we I mean
we took him my first draft. We extended
them. Um you know Rocket he's
outperformed how we acquired him signing
him as an undrafted free agent. um
Emanuel, it was I mean it we just viewed
it as a fantastic opportunity and
someone who could you know not only just
from a pure talent standpoint improve
the room but could also complement our
existing core there. Andrew,
>> um uh you spoke back in January about
dedicating a lot of resources to
remaking this offense
>> with one day still left in the draft. Do
you where do you how do you how do you
feel about the process you've done in
terms of that remodeling?
>> Uh I think we're excited about the
players that we've added. Um we're
certainly excited to see them on the
grass because we haven't seen them as a
collective unit. Um, you know, but we
still have we still have work to do on
both sides of the ball and and and
tomorrow will be a big day for that, but
um, you know, so will, you know, really
made to the cut down period because
there are still some um important roles
that we'd like to add competition to.
>> You said you don't want to put too much
on Emanuel's plate too soon. Do you see
him initially as kind of a ballhawk free
safety?
>> I think that remains to be seen, uh,
Tony. Um, and and honestly like that
determination will be by, you know,
Monk, Rudy, Ephraim. Um,
yeah, I I it's it's probably hard for me
to answer that till he's like in our
building until we get him up in up and
running. Um, but, you know, we'll we'll
crawl, walk, run. Andrew, I know you
have to stay flexible during the draft,
but did you anticipate a scenario where
you might take two receivers either back
to back or whatever early on in this
draft? And does it feel like like a
departure because you really hadn't done
that in your previous drafts there
taking receiver high? Scott, we did um
we did have scenarios where because of
the strength of the receiver class and
the depth of it that we thought we could
take um you know two receivers
relatively high definitely doesn't feel
like a departure. It's maybe a little
bit you know what I mentioned to Fred
earlier where I think if you look at the
past couple years you know we had we had
Jarvis and Odell um you know we traded
for Amari who was a Pro Bowl receiver
for us and then you know had him on a
big money extension. We then traded
Jerry for Jerry who was a Pro Bowl
receiver for us. Um and then like I was
actually even thinking um and this this
one didn't maybe work out quite as
cleanly but even the years where we were
short first round picks you know one of
those trades was for Elijah Moore and
then you know trading down from two for
Elijah Moore and then uh taking set in
three. So there's no philosophical thing
there. It's obviously easier to to maybe
dictate the room a little bit more when
you have your full slate of resources.
>> I was just asking thought about how the
quarterbacks looked on the last two days
of mini camp because we didn't get to
see any of that. Um, so just wondering
how comfortable are you with the
quarterback room right now and what are
you still thinking that it's wholly
realistic to possibly add somebody to
the room on the third day of the draft?
>> Yeah, we'll always add talent at the
most important position. That's that's
that's, you know, I guess full stop.
Doesn't matter who's in the room. If
there's a quarterback that we'll like
that's available to us at the right
cost, um, we'll add that player. Um, you
know, that being said, the three guys
have done a really nice job so far this
spring. You know, we're lucky that we
got three days on the grass. Um, you
know, they all are are learning the
offense quickly. Um, you know, working
through their mistakes, throwing the
ball, throwing the ball well. Um, but,
you know, that wouldn't that wouldn't
um, you know, prevent us from adding a
player that we like tomorrow.
>> You were gaming all this stuff out. Was
there a scenario where you had your
first four picks, all this Cleveland
Browns? I mean, just I, you know, seems
like four players that a lot of people
had first round grades on and you know,
I know a couple years ago with JK, you
felt like you got one there, but it
feels like you got two of them here.
>> Yeah, I I think um you know, as we
worked through scenarios, as we worked
through simulations, uh we did have
simulations where the receivers kind of
lined up the way that they did um just
because of the strength of this class.
You know, I'll be honest. I I did not
anticipate a world where um Emanuel went
as late as he did.
>> And what about the kind of stutter step
out of the third round then back in? Did
you overlook Austin?
>> Oh, no. So, I actually called those
yo-yo trades. So like sometimes you get
um a situation actually probably the
first time I started calling it was that
when we um moved back in it's actually
Sashi I think we moved back in 17
um picked up a future one and I think we
moved back up for for David at the end
of one. Um, oftentimes those trades
become like if you look at the aggregate
set of moves, they become pretty
efficient because you pick up either a
high level or future asset. Um, but
you're able to still get a targeted
player without giving all those realized
gains back. Very rare situations will we
do that, but we felt like this was one
where it made the most sense. Do
>> you have a special affinity for the
fifth round? And uh,
>> the fifth round is the new seventh, Mary
Kay. Yeah. So,
>> what's the thinking going into tomorrow
with four?
>> You know, honestly, in day three of the
draft because teams, boards, they they
they just spread out there there's
there's very little overlap. Truth be
told, you could largely go into the
third day of the draft with maybe call
like eight to 10 names and you're
probably going to get you're probably
going to get most of them. So, it it
it'll literally be, hey, how can we be
as opportunistic as possible because
you're just not going to be able to
predict, you know, predict the order of
uh, you know, the players that go off. I
was joking with Todd upstairs. I was
like, man, I I got apologize. I misread
the market because,
um, you know, we thought we were going
to be able to maybe add one of the
class's strongest, you know, blocking
tight ends, you know, with one of those
fifth round picks. And, you know, pretty
much all of them went off the board by
the end of the third round. So, I was
like, I screwed that one up. I messed
that up. So, we'll just take the best
opportunity that we can with the players
that are available. I don't know who
mentioned it earlier. If there if there
comes a situation where there's a u a
veteran trade that makes sense, we would
explore that as we always do. But, um
our big thing is how do we best maximize
the assets
>> with the barber trade? Um do you see
Todd said you see first as a tackle
>> um so is that just about I mean
obviously you traded or signed traded
for Titus and then drafted Spencer. So,
is it just that position is so important
that you want to get as much depth
outside?
>> Yeah, I mean I also think like you know
we talked about turning over that
position group um with both youth and
talent and um Titus is great. Um he can
play tackle, he can play guard. Um but
also being realistic that um you know he
is a little bit more advanced in his
career, you know, relatives to some of
the other players. But you can never you
can never have enough of the of the
tackles. you can never have enough of
the, you know, the line of scrimmage
players just because they're so hard to
find and they're so hard to acquire once
you get past this point that um we want
to roll deep in those position groups
when we can.
>> Andrew, looking at the players that have
gone first 100, only three running
backs, do you attribute it to class? Do
you attribute it to I mean just in in
your, you know, kind of your scouting of
that position? Like can you what what
would you attribute?
>> I think it's two things. I think it's
class and I also think it's um just the
fact that if you go back to last year's
class how deep it was. I think a lot of
teams took took their young running
backs. I mean look we took two um and so
I think that plays into it as well. Do
you have a why Emanuel fell like he did?
>> I don't just some sometimes that happens
just happens.
goes back to fatigue and all of this.
Obviously, you know, analyzing all these
players, match them up against each
other, knowing how long the draft is
11:00.
How like important to kind of keep the
energy?
>> You know, try it's way past my bedtime.
So, I I that that is one of the hardest
parts of this weekend. You just get or I
speak for myself, I get so drained. one
because I'm an early morning person and
then two just from everything that
you're doing um you know in terms of of
trying to manage and direct you know the
evening the day the quick turnaround um
and then also just all the like kind of
the ancillary obligations that that come
as part of it. Um they are long days so
>> think about the move to eight minutes in
the first round. love it like like yes
this may be unpopular but I would make
it seven minutes if we can. So yes
the patience you thought you guys showed
by not moving up staying there then
Denzel makes it to you guys and then
obviously you made a couple other moves
when you went up. So what would you say
is a determining factor to when it's hey
we're going to stay and wait and hope
versus let's go get back. I mean, you're
you're really trying to just play the
odds and and and when I say that, it's
it's not just like this black bods,
okay, this guy has whatever percentage
chance of getting there. It's pulling
um you know, the information that you
can source. It's looking at your board
and and identifying the group of players
that you're comfortable with sitting and
picking or you know, if you have to move
u and then at that point, it's making an
educated guess. Like look, we did
consider, okay, if we're at 39, is there
a move that would make sense to go up
and get Denzel or go up and get, you
know, Emanuel and after going through
all the information, having discussion,
um, you know, kind of trying to read the
board as the picks came off, we felt
like the right decision, the right bet
was to remain to remain patient. And you
don't get all those right. Um, you know,
so, you know, you just make the best
decisions you can in the moment.
How much fun has it been just having
Todd there first? I saw the videos.
>> How are the wise?
>> It's it's it's great cuz like Todd is
super funny and um unfortunately all of
it can't make it on camera with how
funny he is, but he is he keeps the room
energetic. He keeps it light. He's super
passionate. Um he's he's a lot of fun to
work with. Yeah. So
>> share any of those Ask him that the next
time he comes down here. How about that?
All right, you guys have a good night.